We'll have the invocation for the pastor of the first Christian
church, Mr. Brandon Fletcher.
Let's pray.
Father God, we love you.
God, we come to you just thankful to have
the opportunity to live in a great community.
And God, I just pray over tonight's meeting,
pray over all the decisions that will be made,
the discussions that will be had.
And God, I pray that you give just extra resilience and grit
to make the right decisions, to have peace, to have unity,
so that we can continue moving forward
and continue the momentum that's been
gained in the last several years.
God, we ask that you bless our community.
And we just ask that we would glorify you through that.
And Father, most importantly, make us more like Jesus.
In Jesus' name we pray.
Amen.
I pledge allegiance to the flag of the United States of America
and to the republic for which it stands, one nation
under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all.
I implore public input on scheduled personal preferences.
We have none.
5A, discussion, and possible action on the claims list.
Can I make a motion?
Will you approve?
Second.
Is that?
Hi.
Barnes.
Jones.
Hi.
Dunkel.
Harper.
Hi.
5B, discussion, and possible action on the minutes
for the May 19, 2026 regular meeting.
Motion to approve.
Second.
Dunkel.
Hi.
Is that?
Jones.
Hi.
Barnes.
Harper.
Hi.
5C, discussion, and possible action
on budget amendment 26-11, moving funds to 515 Utility
Improvement Fund to cover April and June loan payments,
and moving budgeted Oklahoma Water Resource Board grant
and expenditures from automated metering infrastructure
and water treatment to 515 Utility Improvement Fund.
Crystal.
Yes, thank you.
This basically does two things.
We had some funds that were already spent under 512,
and we decided to track all those funds under 515
where everything would be siloed in one spot,
and we'd be able to track those projects a little bit better.
And then this moves money from already budgeted money from 510
to 515 to make our first loan payment.
I'll make a motion to approve.
Second.
Jones.
Hi.
Barnes.
East End.
Hi.
Dunkel.
Harper.
Hi.
5B, discussion, and possible action on fiscal year 2026,
2027 budget.
OK, so we're going to go ahead and talk
about the MSUA budget.
It can be discussion only.
You guys can approve.
It's up to you totally.
We still have plenty of time to do either.
First of all, I want to thank everybody
that helped with the budget.
It's been about a three month process to get here,
so it doesn't go lightly that we don't spend a lot of time
on this.
Some of the highlights that I want to hit on this budget
are under admin services.
You'll see materials.
There's $11.4 million budgeted for that.
That is the purchase power coming from GRDA,
so that's why that number is so big.
There is a new.
The new Fiber Department is budgeted.
Let me see.
What you won't find in this budget is the Fiber and AMI
budget, $14.1 million, because we've already
done that in this fiscal year, and that will just roll over
and be re-encumbered next fiscal year,
so that's why that number is missing from here.
The GRDA money from the settlement
is setting in reserves, drawing interest,
and it is not technically budgeted anywhere at this time.
We're just kind of waiting to see where that money needs
to go.
So we have received all of those payments?
We have received the full settlement, so.
Just a few highlights.
We're trying to keep MSUA competitive.
The wage is competitive for the region.
$500,000 out of this budget goes to help Street Nally,
so that's where some of our street money comes from.
And then $2.94 transfer to General Fund
helps the operation on the city side.
That's kind of the highlights that I had.
If you guys have any questions, I'd
be happy to try to answer them.
Or if you need more time to look at it,
and I can always be reached at any time.
And I'll go a little more in-depth on the budget
presentation on the city side of how all this stuff works
together and kind of where the pools of money come from.
But this is just strictly MSUA's budget.
Once the budget is set and approved and set in motion
for the next year, that's online for anyone
to see that wants to go look at it from the community.
Yes, I believe we post all those documents online
on the website.
Tyler, you have anything to add?
I was going to say, can you talk about how we pretty much
have two offices that we do the pre-audit with Crawford
and then we do the.
Yeah, so the way that things work on the state side,
especially with the municipalities,
we have a set of auditors that come in and basically close
our books for us.
They do all the financial statements
and all the legwork to kind of prep it,
and then it goes to audit.
So basically, everything is looked at double,
because we have the people that we
are contractually hired to help us get everything packaged
together, and then we have an actual external set
of auditors that come in and look at everything.
Is that something we're required to do,
or is that just something we do?
I don't think it's a requirement.
I think it's very common in Oklahoma for it to be that way.
The last conversation that I had with our auditors about it
is their audit firm will not even go out to bid an audit
unless this package deal kind of happens before.
So it's not an actual state stature or anything
that we have to do that.
It's just kind of common in Oklahoma
that you have some prep work done before.
It just cleans everything up before it actually goes to audit.
I know those audits also posted.
Yes.
Anyone in the community can go look at them.
Chris, there's been some questions
come up recently about the number of transfers we're doing.
Can you touch on some of the reason
why we do the transfers we do and how all that works?
Sure.
So a lot of the transfers, if you
will look at this box right here,
it explains a lot of what happens.
So MSUA is paying back rainy day fund to build that nest egg.
MSUA supports part of it.
There's multiple transfers that happen.
So that's why it gets complicated.
MSUA pays on bonds and then there's
sales tax money that was pledged for those bonds.
So there are actual city sales tax money
have to be ran through MSUA and then transferred back
to the city to meet those bond requirements.
So it makes that number look really inflated
because you send all the sales tax over
and then you send the majority of it back.
There's some that doesn't come back.
It stays over there on that side,
but the majority of it comes back.
So out of the 14 million or so transfers,
like almost 8 million of that is just,
it's basically just being washed through MSUA
and coming right back to the city.
And then it funds some other things.
Street Natalie, like I said, gets 500,000.
It's paying some electron improvement bonds.
The fiber and AMI loan is transferred out and paid.
What else?
115,000 goes to the airport taxiway relocation grant.
That's something for that.
It's also supported MDRA in the form of Coleman.
Let's see.
I think those are the major ones.
Did I miss anything, Jill?
Thank you.
Yep.
Anybody have any questions?
Any other questions?
I don't have any questions,
but based on the information
and the questions that I've had from the community,
I wanna recommend that we table this
until our next council meeting
so that we have more time to go through it,
be more thorough and answer some of the questions
that are being proposed.
Absolutely, I agree.
I think.
I'm available anytime.
I think that would be best if there's any.
Okay.
And then I look forward to your deep dive
into the presentation,
so it probably will answer some of those questions.
Sure.
That's my recommendation.
I don't know how everybody else feels, but I agree.
Agreed.
Thank you, guys.
Thank you.
On the 5E Discussion Possible Action
on Work Order Number 1925-04,
amendment number two with Olson Engineering
for Highway 69A for design and easement acquisition
from BNSF Railroad to Buffalo Run Boulevard
for water line, sewer line, electric relocation,
not to exceed $195,300.
Yes, good evening.
This is, just as it says from Buffalo Run
to the railroad tracks, their widening system in A.
Back in January 7th, 2020,
we actually had an amendment
on work order we already entered into with Olson.
This is just for general, for extra funds to,
for the design and the
securement of easement acquisition.
It is for the, like I said, for that design.
It's all reimbursable through OODOT.
They've already approved it.
We just need your approval to move forward
with this work order.
So as everybody knows, this is for the widening of 69A.
You know, there's like four phases of that project.
This is one of those phases.
So I'll make a motion to be approved.
Second?
Step.
Hi.
Barnes.
Jones.
Hi.
Dokel.
Parker.
Hi.
5F Discussion Possible Action on Perpetual Utility
Easement Agreement with the Housing Authority
of the Peoria Tribe of Indians of Oklahoma
for the installation and maintenance of water line
located near the new 69A water tower,
including authorization of one time payment
and the amount of $1 that authorized the trust manager
to execute all necessary documents.
Yep.
So this is that same water line that's going down
treaty road.
This, it will tie, it'll loop feed the Housing Authority
itself, it'll have a separate loop off there.
So we needed an easement to go over about 125 foot
and then down 90 foot to tie into that existing line.
So the Housing Authority will be on a loop also.
It's also ties into this, not this easement,
but it does go on down and it will tie in to the other feed
we have for everybody on that side.
But this is just for the piece that we need with the housing.
Just under 44?
This easement doesn't, but this line does, yes.
OK.
Yep.
This line does not?
No, this line does.
The easement doesn't.
But this easement, this portion of this easement
is not the other, it ties into that one.
The easement is outside of the triangle out there, right?
Yes.
Yeah.
There's a, you guys should have a map in your packet.
And it's that yellow piece.
Oh, I can't get to my map.
Oh, there it is.
Yeah.
OK, that's fine.
Motion to approve.
Second.
Sorry.
Stone Cold.
All right.
Jones, aye.
Barnes, aye.
East End.
Parker.
All right.
5G, discussion of possible action on change of order number one
with McGuire Iron Incorporated for Well 7 Tower Project,
allowing for a 45-day time extension and paint change
to add logo, not to exceed $50,000.
Yes, we, they are too painting it.
The date was May 31st.
We need to extend that at 45 days
so we can get that project completed.
Make motion approved.
Second.
Is that Jones?
Yes.
Thank you.
Jones?
Aye.
Parker?
Stone Cold?
Aye.
East End?
Barnes?
Aye.
5-H, discussion of possible action on proposal
for consulting services with Uptown Services for Fiber
to the PREM, premise, FTPP, implementation, support task,
including construction management,
and network system integration,
authorize the trust manager to negotiate and sign
the contract contingent upon legal review,
not to exceed $487,000.
Yes, Uptown is the ones that has been our design force
for our Fiber project.
We're asking if we can use them for implementation,
support, and construction management,
which would be on an hourly basis and plus travel expense.
And then also for the system installation and entry,
I can't say the word, Keith, what is your act?
Integration.
Thank you.
Wow, that was tough.
Yeah, so it'd be installing the equipment, the servers,
the firewalls, the riders.
And that portion would be a set fee of $100,000.
And then there would be a monthly fee
for the implementation support tasks, which
would be the billing system, the procurement of the bandwidth
where we purchase the bandwidth, help
with the product plan, the service plan, the marketing
plan, and then also with our regulatory compliance issues
that we have with our federal and state.
So that'll be another portion of the monthly fee off of that.
This all be paid out of the money
that we already have budgeted for the Fiber project.
Move motion approved.
Second.
Jones.
Five.
Barn.
All right.
East End.
Donkel.
All right.
Dr.
Six A, discussion on Fiber materials related to contract
C25-85 with border states.
Yes, this is just a discussion.
We don't need a vote on anything.
We just wanted to come back to you and talk to you
about where we are in that process and what that's
looking like so far.
That original quote that we got from them was about $1.4 million.
And we're wanting to take some components, cabinet pieces
themselves, and the way they had them
been before was all the separate pieces.
And we're putting those pieces together.
And we're hoping to reduce that cost down by about 100.
It says $193,000.
But we're hoping that realistic number would be around $150
when we're all done because there's a few other components
that we have to work through on that.
We just wanted to come back to you
and let you know where we were on that process
and that's what we're doing with those things.
I don't know if you guys have any questions about where we are
in that project, if you want to talk about that or if you can.
We just wanted to make you guys aware that we are working
on these things and we're trying to move forward
as fast as we can.
Hopefully, we'll have some materials in six to eight
weeks is the plan.
So we should be moving forward quickly with it.
Any questions?
Any questions from Derek?
Thank you, Derek.
Seven, another new business, if any,
with the businesses associated with this agenda.
Eight, trustee community announcements.
Nine, trust member communications?
No, sir.
Jan, agenda.
OK.
Thank you.
Dumpel?
Aye.
Issa?
Barnes?
Aye.
Williams?
Parker?
Aye.